<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Save Grey District Library Services</title><link>https://save-grey-library.github.io/</link><description>A working group established to save the Greymouth District Library from degradation by GDC policy and proposals.</description><atom:link href="https://save-grey-library.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:GreyLibrary@gmx.com"&gt;Save Grey Library Working Group&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 18:05:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Welcome to the Save Grey District Library Working Group</title><link>https://save-grey-library.github.io/posts/</link><dc:creator>Save Grey Library Working Group</dc:creator><description>&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div align="center"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="+2" color="#5670d4"&gt;Please Sign
          Our Petition Below&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="+2"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;&lt;font size="+2"&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;div align="center"&gt;&lt;img moz-do-not-send="true" src="https://save-grey-library.github.io/images/greymouth.jpg" alt="Grey River Greymouth photo by
        Stewart Nimmo, used under Creative Copywright licence" width="800" height="533"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;font size="-1"&gt;Photo by Stewart Nimmo used under creative
        copyright license CC BY-SA 4.0&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;font size="+1"&gt;If you believe that the provision of a quality
        library service requires appropriately qualified librarians who
        have input into the management of library services then please
        sign our petition.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      (Link to Petition)&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;font size="-1"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/font&gt;As reported in the Greymouth Star 25th October 2022 -
      "managerial positions at .... the Grey District Library would be
      disestablished and replaced with supervisors". This action is part
      of the Grey District Council CEO's Change Proposal. In subsequent
      responses to letters to the editor Council CEO Paul Morris has
      indicated that because Council plans to construct a new library
      building it is not degrading library services. Although the Save
      Grey District Library Working Group acknowledges the need for a
      new library building it distinguishes between the provision of a
      library service and the construction of a building at some future
      date. Paul Morris, the Grey District Mayor and Councillors do not
      seem to accept this distinction, and seem to believe that a
      library building without qualified librarians in management
      positions still amounts to a library service - &lt;b&gt;we do not agree
        with this point of view. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;br&gt;
      Individual Grey District Councillors and the Mayor may wish to
      correct the record by making a public statement in support of
      qualified library management being resourced to run the Grey
      District Library Service, at which time we will amend these
      statements to indicate which Councillors support qualified library
      managers for the provision of quality library services. At this
      point however the Mayor has made it quite clear in previous press
      statements that Paul Morris has her complete support for his
      proposals. Other Councillors as far as we can see from a search of
      the media  have remained silent on this matter and therefore
      given their tacit approval for the Mayor and CEO's stance. Again
      we are prepared to amend this webpage if any Councillor or the
      Mayor are willing to make a public statement that they are opposed
      to the proposal as outlined by Council CEO Paul Morris.&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      This website is the work of the Save Grey District Library Working
      Group. It is not associated with or necessarily endorsed by the
      Grey District Library or the Grey District Council. It has been
      established by a group of concerned Grey District citizens who are
      worried about the future of Library Services in the Grey District
      and the Council CEO's proposal to remove library management and
      downgrade the role of qualified librarians.&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Council</category><category>Grey District</category><category>Library</category><guid>https://save-grey-library.github.io/posts/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>